

VISUAL / PRODUCT DESIGNER

CONTACT

daniel.rajendran@gmail.com



WORK

- danielrajendran.co.uk
- behance.net/danielrajendran
- linkedin.com/in/danielrajendran

SKILLS

Process: Wireframing, Rapid prototyping, Agile development, Responsive design, High-fidelity design, Web design, User journeys, Storytelling, Interaction design

Applications: Sketch, Figma, Adobe XD, Miro, Mural, Marvel, InVision, Balsamig, Zeplin, InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator

Technology: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, PHP

Systems: Pendo, Product Board, Google Analytics, Jira, HotJar, WordPress, Jekyll, Marketo, SalesForce, MailChimp, Aprimo, Eloqua, SharePoint

Other: Photo editing, Photography, Copy writing, Illustration, Iconography

ABOUT

I'm a multi-format designer with over 14 years of experience working in fast-paced tech companies. I've experienced the rush of rapid start-up growth, the pressure of a big partnership with Facebook, and the ever-shifting priorities of work at a consultancy. In my different roles I've gained experience working across many design mediums, and over time I've found my passion is to design and build beautiful things, from icons and apps to posters and products.

I'm happiest as part of a team where I can learn from others and improve my own skills. I've learned from experience that research and data gathering are inherent to making good decisions, and that collaborative iteration is a key part of my role. I've got a proven ability to deliver on time, relish learning new skills, and always strive to embrace challenges outside of my comfort zone.

EXPERIENCE



Senior Product Designer for Proximie HEALTHTECH TELEPRESENCE DATA VIS October 2022 - April 2023



- Worked across the Core, Live, Mobile, and Wearable teams, supporting multiple product streams with design tasks at various stages product life cycle
- Lead all design efforts for new data visualisation and reporting features for the Proximie web platform, to provide users and organisations with insight into their activity and usage
- Saw features from discovery through to release, including problem definition, user research, sketches, prototyping, user testing, high-fidelity design creation, and feedback gathering
- Supported go-to-market of new wearable camera hardware with designs for companion mobile apps on iOS and Android, as well as illustrations for user manuals



Senior Product Designer (UI) for Concirrus INSURETECH RISK ANALYSIS DATA VIS March 2019 - July 2022

- Lead all design efforts for Quest Automotive, a SaaS web platform designed to provide risk management insight and visualisation for automotive insurance companies
- Migrated Quest Automotive from Sketch to Figma and established a cross-product component library to develop a shared design language between our three core product teams
- Designed and prototyped a mobile app for our first internal hackathon, to deliver key features of the Quest Automotive web app to fleet managers operating in the field
- Lead discovery and design of a new 'Submissions' feature for Quest Marine, to allow marine insurance underwriters to more easily assess the potential risk of in-bound business
- Rebuilt the component library to take advantage of new Figma features, whilst reducing complexity and duplication of work
- Lead initiative to incorporate a newly acquired product into our portfolio, including rebranding as Quest Property, evaluating existing features, and scoping new feature designs



Product Designer for Content and Code SHAREPOINT OFFICE 365 INTRANET June 2017 — February 2019

- A key part of driving Fresh, the company's Intranet-In-A-Box, through several major product milestones, designing key new features that improved usability and increased sales
- Designed the Fresh Mobile app for iOS/Android from the ground up
- Supported a major platform transition to rebuild Fresh using Modern SharePoint
- Lead a project to update the Fresh visual brand, adapting the original pop-art styling to be usable in more situations and formats, without sacrificing the unique visual identity
- Designed all new features and layouts for Fresh, updating existing UI components to suit
- Completely redesigned the Content and Code and Fresh commercial websites to improve user flow and site load times, and reduce overhead caused by over-reliance on WordPress plugins



VISUAL / PRODUCT DESIGNER

CONTACT

daniel.rajendran@gmail.com

07708698413

WORK

- danielrajendran.co.uk
- behance.net/danielrajendran
- linkedin.com/in/danielrajendran

REFERENCES

Available upon request

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)



Front-End Designer/Developer for DataSift BIG DATA SOCIAL MEDIA INSIGHT January 2015 - December 2016



- Played an instrumental part in launching our Facebook Topic Data platform, creating new web content and print collateral, as well as co-ordinating launch of said content
- Lead a project to move legacy sites from Drupal to WordPress for easier management
- Ran 'Lunch and Learn' sessions about how design and branding serves the business
- Designed new lead tracking and scoring systems to greatly improve website lead quality
- Responsible for design, coding, QA, and maintenance for all commercial websites
- Assisted the product team with visual design and UX prototyping for a new product offering
- Designed numerous ebooks, one pagers, banners, and other sales and marketing collateral



Web Designer for Huddle CLOUD COLLABORATION FILE SHARING DIGITAL MARKETING

- January 2010 December 2014
- Primary design and development resource for the commercial side of the company, supporting marketing, sales, and customer success
- Handled end to end process for the marketing site, blog, and help desk, including page design, coding, QA, deployment and maintenance, as well as copywriting and illustration
- Designed all marketing and sales collateral, including one-pagers, ebooks, event branding, business cards, ad banners, and merchandise
- Lead a team that completely redesigned the home page and free trial flow to increase lead generation by nearly 200% and greatly increase lead quality
- · Assisted in a complete company rebrand, and then lead a full redesign of the marketing site
- Help establish key aspects of the company culture, such as hackathons, social clubs, bakeoffs, and charity events

EDUCATION



BSc Computing and Interaction Design at Goldsmiths College, University of London September 2006 - August 2009

- Focused on web design and technologies, user experience, and interaction design
- Covered computer science topics such as object oriented programming and database design
- Final project was a human interaction device that could manipulate 3D models in real-time.



BEng Computer and Network Engineering at University of Westminster September 2004 - Jan 2006

- Computer science style degree that focused on network engineering and programming
- Also included foundational topics such as electrical engineering and applied mathematics
- Transferred during my 2nd year to pursue a more design oriented degree